<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-02T22:06:53-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Bionotes</title><subtitle>Bionotes is a site where students can access free notes from courses that they take.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bacteria and Archaea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/campbell/2019/10/15/tech-addiciton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bacteria and Archaea" /><published>2019-10-15T15:08:25-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-15T15:08:25-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/campbell/2019/10/15/tech-addiciton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/campbell/2019/10/15/tech-addiciton.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The first organisms to inhabit Earth were prokaryotes that lived 3.5 bilion years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prokaryotic-structure&quot;&gt;Prokaryotic Structure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most prokaryotes are unicellular and are much smaller than eukaryotic cells.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Cell Wall&lt;/strong&gt; retains cell shape, protection, and prevents it from bursting in a hypotonic environment.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In eukaryotes like plants and fungi usualy have cell walls made of cellulose or chitin. Bacterial cells contain cell walls made of &lt;strong&gt;peptidoglycan&lt;/strong&gt;, which are made by modified sugars and polypeptides.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Archaeal cell walls contain proteins and polysaccharides but &lt;strong&gt;lack peptidoglycan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The first organisms to inhabit Earth were prokaryotes that lived 3.5 bilion years ago.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/mvDefSRl3EkSEt_YfsLjeg--~A/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjtzbT0xO3c9ODAw/https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2019-08/24565700-c5c8-11e9-ab5b-903ae75b5966" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/campbell/2019/10/12/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2019-10-12T15:08:25-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T15:08:25-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/campbell/2019/10/12/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/campbell/2019/10/12/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://michael-kuehnel.de/assets/img/jekyll-logo.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Study Biology?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/diversity/2019/10/12/Notion-Documentation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Study Biology?" /><published>2019-10-12T15:08:25-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T15:08:25-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/diversity/2019/10/12/Notion%20Documentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/diversity/2019/10/12/Notion-Documentation.html">&lt;p&gt;You might be wondering what the hell this application does. In this article we will go through the documentation and uses of this website and how you can apply this to your individual learning success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;usage-beyond-the-classroom&quot;&gt;Usage Beyond The Classroom&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we use Notion while learning independantly? Here we will list some reasons to use this when you are home or just want to learn some new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; title=&quot;presidium-tooltip&quot;&gt;Tooltips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You might be wondering what the hell this application does. In this article we will go through the documentation and uses of this website and how you can apply this to your individual learning success.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.minhajcollege.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/ALevel-Biology-1170x560.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Pass A Lie Detector Test</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/12/how-to-pass-a-lie-detector.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Pass A Lie Detector Test" /><published>2019-10-12T15:08:25-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T15:08:25-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/12/how-to-pass-a-lie-detector</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/12/how-to-pass-a-lie-detector.html">&lt;p&gt;A polygraph test or lie detector test is designed to analyze physiological reactions to questions to determine whether or not a subject is being truthful. The accuracy of the test has been widely contested by groups including the National Academy of Science, the US Congress Office of Technology Assessment, and the American Psychological Association. Even so, the test is routinely used to screen employment applicants and interrogate criminal suspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a person may be told to answer all questions honestly, the test is designed to measure responses to “white lies,” which means truly honest people run the risk of generating a false positive on the test. Other people may wish to conceal answers to certain questions, whether guilty of wrongdoing or not. Fortunately for them, it’s not that hard to beat a lie detector test. The first step to passing the test is understanding how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-a-lie-detector-test-works&quot;&gt;How a Lie Detector Test Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lie detector test includes more than the time spent hooked up to the polygraph machine. The tester will start making observations the instant a person enters the test center. A skilled polygrapher will notice and record nonverbal cues associated with lying, so it’s a good idea to know your “tells”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The polygraph machine records breathing rate, blood pressure, pulse rate, and perspiration. More sophisticated machines include magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the brain. Physiological responses to irrelevant, diagnostic, and relevant questions are compared to identify lies. Questions may be repeated two to three times. The subject may be asked to intentionally lie to help the examiner establish baseline values. The test typically requires one to three hours to complete, including the background assessment, medical history, explanation of the test, actual polygraph, and follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Advice Isn’t Very Effective
The internet is filled with advice on ways to beat a lie detector test, but many of these ideas aren’t very effective. For example, biting your tongue or putting a tack in your shoe to use pain to affect blood pressure won’t affect perspiration levels. Similarly, imagining a lie when telling the truth and imagining the truth when telling a lie won’t work because it establishes differences between lies and truth. Remember, differences between the truth and lies are the basis for the test!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 Ways to Beat the Test
Basically, there are two good ways to beat the test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be completely zen, no matter what you’re asked. Note: Most people can’t master this.
Be completely distraught throughout the entire test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 Tips to Try
Most people are nervous when taking a lie detector test, whether they intend to lie or not. The physical responses to nerves probably won’t fool a lie detector. You need to up your game to simulate feelings of mortal terror. This is because beating the test is all about mind games, which naturally affect physical responses. Here are some tips to try:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to beat the test, your best bet is to stay upset, fearful and confused throughout the entire test. The goal is to appear calm and in control, despite the inner turmoil. Remember your worst experience or solve difficult math problems in your head—whatever keeps you in a constant state of excitation and stress. If there is one particular question you’re worried about, imagine every question is that question before answering.
Take time before answering any question. Identify it as irrelevant, relevant, or diagnostic (control). Irrelevant questions include asking you to confirm your name or whether the lights are on in the room. Relevant questions are the important ones. An example would be, “Did you know about the crime?” Diagnostic questions are ones most people should answer “yes” to but will most likely lie about. Examples include, “Have you ever taken anything from your workplace?” or “Have you ever lied to get out of trouble?”
Alter your breathing during control questions, but return to normal breathing before answering the next question. You can make minor admissions here or not, as you choose.
When you answer questions, answer firmly, without hesitation, and without humor. Be cooperative, but don’t joke or act overly-friendly.
Answer “yes” or “no” whenever possible. Do not explain answers, give details, or offer explanations. If asked to expand on a question, reply: “What more do you want me to say?” or “There’s really nothing to say about that.”
If accused of lying, don’t fall for it. If anything, use the accusation as fuel to feel upset and confused. In fact, answering diagnostic questions honestly may have given the examiner conflicting results, so be prepared to be questioned further.
Practice any countermeasures before the test. Ask someone to ask you likely questions. Be aware of your breathing and how you react to different types of questions.
Keep in mind, applying these tips may enable you to invalidate the test, but won’t be much use if you’re taking a lie detector test to get a job. In most cases, the easiest way through a lie detector test is to approach it honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drugs That Affect Tests
Drugs and medical conditions may affect a polygraph test, often leading to an inconclusive result. For this reason, drug tests and a screening questionnaire are commonly given before a lie detector test. Medications that affect heart rate and blood pressure can affect polygraph results. These include antihypertensives and anti-anxiety medications and also a host of illegal drugs, including heroin, marijuana, cocaine, and methamphetamine. Caffeine, nicotine, allergy medications, sleep aids, and cough remedies may also affect the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Medical Conditions May Prohibit the Test
While diagnosed sociopaths and psychopaths may be excluded from the test due to a potential ability to control responses, other medical conditions may prohibit the test. People who have epilepsy, nerve damage (including essential tremor), heart disease, have suffered a stroke, or are extremely fatigued should not take the test. Mentally incompetent people shouldn’t take the test. Pregnant women are generally exempted from the test unless a doctor gives written approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the exception of mental illness, drugs and medical conditions don’t necessarily enable a person to beat a lie detector test. However, they do skew the results, making them less reliable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources
Board on Behavioral, Cognitive, and Sensory Sciences and Education (BCSSE) and Committee on National Statistics (CNSTAT) (2003). “The Polygraph and Lie Detection”. National Research Council (Chapter 8: Conclusions and Recommendations), p. 21.
“Scientific Validity of Polygraph Testing: A Research Review and Evaluation”. Washington, D. C.: U.S. Congress Office of Technology Assessment. 1983.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A polygraph test or lie detector test is designed to analyze physiological reactions to questions to determine whether or not a subject is being truthful. The accuracy of the test has been widely contested by groups including the National Academy of Science, the US Congress Office of Technology Assessment, and the American Psychological Association. Even so, the test is routinely used to screen employment applicants and interrogate criminal suspects.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.thoughtco.com/thmb/TyGz3Bkx72mOULMUIxXlv7llWmY=/768x0/filters:no_upscale():max_bytes(150000):strip_icc():format(webp)/fbi-lie-detector-test-521967202-59b7ff6622fa3a0011489b69.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Lizard Dilemma: Evolution?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/12/phylogetic-tree-of-lizards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Lizard Dilemma: Evolution?" /><published>2019-10-12T15:08:25-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T15:08:25-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/12/phylogetic-tree-of-lizards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/12/phylogetic-tree-of-lizards.html">&lt;p&gt;The Caribbean is home to about 150 species of anole lizards. How do these lizards evolve and become distict from one another?. Four different concepts of &lt;strong&gt;evolutionary biology&lt;/strong&gt; are at play here: adaptation, convergent evolution, phylogenetic analysis, reproductive isolation, and speciation. This article will take you through the real life application of phylogenetic analysis within a specific species of organisms. Feel free to check out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet&quot;&gt;interactive graph&lt;/a&gt; to better understand the lizards evolutionary tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The 700 islands of the Caribbean are home to about 150 species of anoles, a group of lizards of the genus Anolis. These lizards live in diverse habitats and vary greatly in size and other &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikipedia.com/lizards/&quot;&gt;physical characteristics&lt;/a&gt;, such as leg and tail length and skin color and pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are there so many species of anoles? And how did they evolve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer these &lt;a href=&quot;https://google.com&quot;&gt;questions&lt;/a&gt;, four distinct concepts must be approached and understood:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecomorphs&lt;/strong&gt;. Species of Caribbean anoles can be categorized into groups, called ecomorphs, according to their body characteristics (morphology) and the ecological niches they occupy. In this module, you will take measurements of lizards from species belonging to four different ecomorph groups.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phylogeny&lt;/strong&gt;. Analysis of the DNA sequences of certain genes reveals the evolutionary relationships among different anole species. In this module, you will build a phylogenetic tree of anole species to study how the different species evolved.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experimental Data&lt;/strong&gt;. What happens when lizards that belong to a particular ecomorph group are placed in a different habitat? In this module you will collect and analyze data from an experiment designed to answer that question.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dewlap Colors&lt;/strong&gt;. No two lizard species living in the same habitat share the same type of dewlap, the flap of skin under their throats that male anoles display to attract females. In this module, you will characterize two species of lizards based on their dewlap color.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Caribbean is home to about 150 species of anole lizards. How do these lizards evolve and become distict from one another?. Four different concepts of evolutionary biology are at play here: adaptation, convergent evolution, phylogenetic analysis, reproductive isolation, and speciation. This article will take you through the real life application of phylogenetic analysis within a specific species of organisms. Feel free to check out this interactive graph to better understand the lizards evolutionary tree.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.thesprucepets.com/thmb/foqdkh8lTycf7LqFYFX7H887Llo=/960x0/filters:no_upscale():max_bytes(150000):strip_icc()/88521688-56a2bcf93df78cf7727961f7.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What Causes Loss of Biodiversity?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/diversity/2019/10/12/what-causes-loss-of-biodiversity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Causes Loss of Biodiversity?" /><published>2019-10-12T15:08:25-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T15:08:25-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/diversity/2019/10/12/what-causes-loss-of-biodiversity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/diversity/2019/10/12/what-causes-loss-of-biodiversity.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habitat Loss and Fragmentation&lt;/strong&gt;:
A habitat is the place where a plant or animal naturally lives. Habitat loss is identified as main threat to 85% of all species described as threatened or endangered. Factors responsible for this are deforestation, fire and over-use and urbanization.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over-exploitation for Commercialization&lt;/strong&gt;: 
Over-exploitation of resources has coasted more environmental degradation than earning. For example; shrimp farming in India, Thailand, Ecuador and Indonesia results in Wetland destruction, pollution of coastal waters and degradation of coastal fisheries. Scientific studies have concluded that cost of environmental degradation resulting from shrimp farming was costing more than the earning through shrimp exports.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invasive Species&lt;/strong&gt;:
Invasive species are ‘alien’ or ‘exotic’ species which are introduced accidentally or intentionally by human. These species become established in their new environment and spread unchecked, threatening the local biodiversity. These invasive alien species have been identified as the second greatest threat to biodiversity after habitat loss.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pollution&lt;/strong&gt;:
Pollution is a major threat to biodiversity, and one of the most difficult problems to overcome; Pollutants do not recognize international boundaries. For example, agricultural run-off, which contains a variety of fertilizers and pesticides, may seep into ground water and rivers before ending up in the ocean. Atmospheric pollutants drift with prevailing air currents and are deposited far from their original source.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Climate Change&lt;/strong&gt;:
Many climatologists believe that the greenhouse effect is likely to raise world temperatures by about 2°C by 2030, meaning that sea levels will rise by around 30-50 cm by this time. Global warming, coupled with human population growth and accelerating rates of resource use will bring further losses in biological diversity. Vast areas of the world will be inundated causing loss of human life as well as ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Population Growth and Over-consumption&lt;/strong&gt;:
From a population of one billion at the beginning of the 19th century, our species now numbers more than six billion people. Such rapid population growth has meant a rapid growth in the exploitation of natural resources— water, foods and minerals. Although there is evidence that our population growth rate is beginning to slow down, it is clear that the exploitation of natural resources is currently not sustainable. Added to this is the fact that 25 per cent of the population consumes about 75 per cent of the world’s natural resources. This problem of over-consumption is one part of the broader issue of unsustainable use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Illegal Wildlife Trade&lt;/strong&gt;:
The international trade in wild plants and animals is enormous. Live animals are taken for the pet trade, or their parts exported for medicines or food. Plants are also taken from the wild for their horticultural or medicinal value.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Species extinction&lt;/strong&gt;:
Extinction is a natural process. The geological record indicates that many hundreds of thousands of plant and animal species have disappeared over the eras as they have failed to adapt to changing conditions. Recent findings however indicate that the current rate of species extinction is at least a hundred to a thousand times higher than the natural rate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Habitat Loss and Fragmentation: A habitat is the place where a plant or animal naturally lives. Habitat loss is identified as main threat to 85% of all species described as threatened or endangered. Factors responsible for this are deforestation, fire and over-use and urbanization.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://c4.wallpaperflare.com/wallpaper/96/830/538/underwater-sea-fish-coral-wallpaper-preview.jpg" /></entry></feed>